#### **Skills and Summary**

Δ	h	^	 ŧ	m	Δ	

Recent graduate with CS and Math Major. I have strong knowledge of software fundamentals such as data structures, algorithm design, design patterns in object-oriented programming, functional programming, and operating systems ---- I am doing the LeetCode competitions biweekly so I won't get rusty. I have many experiences in Agile development projects in academic settings. I demonstrated that I can lead/manage scrums under Agile methodologies.

I became interested in web development after my friend introduced me to React.js in Dec. 2020. Now I am self-learning about web development and testing my skills through hackathon events.

# Software Dev Others JavaScript Word HTML/CSS PowerPoint

Java Excel
React.js LaTex

SQL/MySQL Kanban/Trello

C/Shell Slack
Git/ Github Discord Bot

Python Andriod Studio

### **Relevant Experience**

Participated in the course project contest with a group of five; Using an agile development cycle, we developed an application for statistics students and instructors to manage their work. (Oct 2017 - Dec 2017)

- Made up user stories and tasks based on the client's needs
- Used spreadsheets to manage tasks weekly
- Developed the front end of the app
- Linked the MySQL database APIs to the front end
- Presented our prototype to the instructor

## Led a group of four to design a new interface for Toad for Oracle, including an interactive prototype and software tutorial. (April 2018 - Aug 2018)

- Interviewed two Database Management software users for our data gathering
- Rolled out details for our GUI's requirements
- Data gathering (interviews and artifacts) from potential clients
- Evaluated our interface prototype based on the traversing times and user feedbacks

### Participated in group projects simulating an open-source contribution process for the popular python library matplotlib (Jan 2019 - Mar 2019):

- Took on the position of scrum master for two working weeks
- Followed agile development process and meeting minutes
- Utilized object-oriented design patterns, and open-source contribution processes
- Provided detailed reports, manual, and convincing acceptance/ unit tests for the issues we have chosen to contribute.

### Developed two React web apps for personal projects and Hackathon events (Dec 2020 - Jan 2021):

- Created reusable React components that can be used in other projects and by other people interested in React.js
- Created cool and interactive CSS animations with CSS transitions and animations
- Used Node.js and Socket.io to run a chat server for my chatbox React component
- For more information, check out my webpage: <a href="mtwangyugeng.github.io/personalpage">mtwangyugeng.github.io/personalpage</a>

#### Education

### **University of Toronto Scarborough Campus (UTSC)**

Graduate - Honours Bachelor of Science (BS)
Major in Computer Science and Major in Mathematics